Orla Coleman

2/21 Rothschild St, Glen Huntly, VIC, 6163

orlaith.coleman@gmail.com 0402467220

Personal Profile

I am a friendly, motivated and hard-working individual.

I spent over three years living in Melbourne, Australia after which I moved home for a year to complete a Higher Diploma in Software Design and Development. This is a conversion course from my original degree in Mathematics & History. The higher diploma is of the same level as my bachelors degree. I also completed a Diploma in Information Technology from the Southern Cross Education Institute.

Skills

- Java
- C#
- ADO.Net
- Angular
- Spring Boot
- Entity Framework
- MySql
- CSS
- Bootstrap & Bootstrap Material Design
- JavaScript
- Node.Js
- Play Framework
- GitHub
- Vagrant
- Virtual box

Work Experience - Software Development

Junior BA Consultant

August 2019 - October 2019

Sogeti Ireland

Client: Insurance Company

Responsibilities:

- Mapping data from different business partners into a data warehouse.
- Creating business rules and document meteirs for the mappings.
- Analysing the data to understand how it works in order to be able to map it correctly.
- Loading data to local database using SSIS.
- Querying the database using SQL language and Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio.
- Understanding the business logic and how the company operates.
- Participating in daily stand-ups.

Sogeti Ireland

Responsibilities:

- Developing in office web application using:
 - o Angular frontend
 - o ASP.Net with Entity Framework
 - Sql database

This is a web application being created to allow answers to be recorded per company in a database and logged with each associated question. Making a currently manual process more automated, and making the data more easily accessible to analyse.

- Requirements gathering for a new system to be put in place with HR
- Running workshops on both projects
 - o wner of the web application workshop

Work Experience - Office

Administration

May 2017 - May 2018

VHIA Melbourne

Responsibilities:

- Front of house reception.
- Answering telephone calls and enquiries.
- Greeting clients upon arrival and showing them to the boardroom.
- Scanning of documents, filing and other admin duties.
- Working with Aptify and other computer programmes
- Scheduling and confirmation of meetings.
- Setting up the Boardroom in preparation for meetings.
- General PA duties for consultants.
- General data-entry duties

Customer Service Consultant

September 2016 – March 2017

Australia Post, Melbourne

Responsibilities:

- Meeting and exceeding KPI's set monthly
- Meet personal/customer service team sales targets and call handling quotos
- Generate sales leads
- Identify and asses customer needs to achieve satisfaction
- Maintain a high level of professionalism while on the phone
- Build sustainable relationships of trust through open and interactive communication
- Working with CRM systems and practices
- Keep records of customer interactions, process customer accounts and file documents

Application Service Representative

May 2016 – August 2016

Yarra Valley Water

- Assess residential property plans before processing applications for water and sewer connections
- Process all land development and building applications, which includes plumbing products and responding to enquiries and completing referrals
- Have a high knowledge of the building industry and its guidelines in Victoria
- Constantly adapt to changing computer systems and working with multiple systems at one time
- Resolve and respond to customer phone calls and emails in an efficient and timely manner with regard to residential developments applications in a professional manner
- Process all Pressure and Flow applications for water services
- Build relationships with developers

Work Experience - Kitchens

The Wee Chief Bar and Restaurant – St. Kilda, Melbourne

February 2015 – May 2016

Cook

Cooking meals to order – on time and well presented

- Maintaining consistent quality in every dish
- Serving up to and over 70 covers a night
- Working alone during full service hours breakfast, lunch and dinner
- Simultaneously using large volume cooking equipment during service
- Food Preparation
- Maintaining the highest standards of food and kitchen hygiene
- Cleaning of the grill and all bench tops
- Maintaining and ordering supplies

The Pint on Punt Bar and Restaurant – St. Kilda, Melbourne

May 2015 – December 2015

<u>Cook – promoted to fill in head chef</u>

- Cooking meals to order on time and well presented
- Maintaining consistent quality in every dish
- Serving up to and over 60 covers both during lunch and dinner
- Working alone during full service hours lunch and dinner
- Maintaining stock levels daily and ordering stock
- Full creative control of the kitchen creating and designing new specials weekly
- Temporary head chef two chefs under my responsibility
- Trained two new chefs
- Budgeting and dealing with food reps in order to keep kitchen costs to a minimum without compromising the quality
- Food Preparation
- Maintaining the highest standards of food and kitchen hygiene
- Cleaning of the grill and all benchtops

Mammys Boy – St. Kilda, Melbourne

May 2015 - August 2015

Cook

Working in high paced fast food restaurant

- Executed daily operations of all stations on line.
- Cleaned work area and food preparation equipment
- Successfully handled opening and closing of the establishment
- Stored food in designated containers and storage areas to prevent spoilage
- Provided excellent customer service in a high-volume, fast paced environment
- Simultaneously operated cooking equipment such as grills and deep-fat fryers during busy service times

Education

National University of Ireland Galway

September 2018 – August 2019

Higher Diploma in Software Design & Development (Level 8)

Southern Cross Educational Institute

March 2017 – May 2018

Diploma in Information Technology

National University of Ireland Galway 2015

September 2011 – August

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Mathematics & History (Level 8)

St Enda's Secondary School, Galway

September 2005 – June

Achieved an all honours & 415 point Leaving Cert result

Additional Information

• Completed volunteer work both overseas in Africa for a period of four weeks, and at home with Operation Christmas Child for 4 years